Agent thinking,
>> Agent.
Foreign.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, welcome back to Agentic Thinking with me.
I have a personal friend, an expert that you got to need
to hear out. This is a PM from Microsoft around Ray Fin
Apps. Chris Anderson, welcome to the show.
I'm very happy to have you here.
People. I'm going to tell you right now, you're going to.
>> Your.
>> Your mind is going to be blown.
For us poor Americans who couldn't get over to fabcon, we're kind
of like, what's the content? What's going on?
We don't know what's happening. I've got the, the creator and, and
PM of what's going on here.
Chris, welcome to the show.
>> Hey Mike. Thanks man. That intro music, I don't know, like I
was just.
>> All right, ready to go, all made by AI.
Like everything we do is AI related now.
Just make it fun, enjoyable. Chris, tell us a bit about what
you do and let's, let's dive in.
I'm really excited. You already knew.
I was wicked excited at Ignite when I made the announcement.
Number one fan, baby. This, this is the future here.
Number one fan. And there has been some major announcements at fabcon
that I. We need to review functions.
We've got secrets, we've got something with copilot going on.
I. I need to download what's going on with this, this fabric
app thing. I think we've just turned a curve here in my
opinion. Like, this is going to be fun to build.
It's going to be highly impactful and I don't think anyone's going
to want to build anything other than these things moving forward because
this is just going to be so cool.
Anyways, take it away. What's going on, Chris?
What are we announcing here? What's new?
>> Is it just funny? It's like, oh, we're going to use this
for everything. Because in my head I'm like, oh, these are all
the things that we still need to get.
So the, the, the biggest ones are, you know, the connectors that
we supported and then the. We had a what I'm going to
call a primitive connector to semantic model that we shipped with at
build. But this is what I'm going to call a true V1
of that connector model. And that really means that we can support
a lot more scenarios for not just how you use it, but
also where you use it and how you develop against it and
it's a lot more controlled. And I'll show you a little bit
about that.
Then the plan is for those connectors to continue to expand.
And it allows you to again, safely control access to data, resources
and things like that. It's set up for you to be able
to control whether that you're connecting as the user who's using the
application or able to connect as effectively like an item identity, a
service identity of some kind. And so sure, ooh, kind of scenarios
where you want a service principal to kind of act as effectively
the auth people are connecting to that really set up a lot
of those things to be able to happen with this new model.
So it's, it's really a great kind of foundation for we want
to go especially, but it also just kind of delivers on what
we really wanted it to be in the first place where, you
know, you don't compromise on the local dev experiences and stuff like
that.
>> Awesome.
>> The other big one is functions, obviously.
So you don't always want all of your code running in the
front end for all different kinds of reasons.
Your browser can only make so many outbound requests at a time.
For example, you might have things that are secrets that you don't
want to expose to the client in the first place.
And lo and behold, we have secrets and functions, finally.
So you cannot just have a backend function, but you can also
use a backend function to Talk to your OpenAI key or whatever
it is that you
>> want to go through to be able to do major.
I think this one right here, the community is going to absolutely
love this feature community. Pay attention to this one.
Functions are going to be your new best friend underneath the hood
of the apps. Like every time I'm building a static web app,
every time I'm building an application, there's a whole pile of APIs
and functions and things happening behind the scenes.
It's not just a GraphQL. So if you build on top of
a SQL database, you get a GraphQL that kind of talks to
the app and it's all secured inside the Microsoft wheelhouse.
But there are things, you know, I'm going to push a couple
ideas here. You're going to want to build a, you know, I've
entered some data, now I want to refresh a pipeline.
Well, you need an API call back to fabric to say, run
this pipe or run this function and load this data.
I believe also with functions, we get the ability, now that a
lakehouse is exposed to us, we can also make a function, snag
a file, upload something, put an image in, and those can be
stored directly down into the lakehouse in the files area.
So. So there's another new connector here.
We're not just talking about semantic models and SQL databases.
We're doing semantic models, SQL databases, data warehouse and now Lakehouse as
all certified, like let's call connectors.
Right. It's just going to work, right?
Kind of things.
>> Yeah. And you know, we also have, I think this also got
announced and if not, I don't think I'm spoiling anything
>> because hey, as long as you say it, I can't say anything.
It's all you, man.
>> The code is. You can find this out and customers have.
And then they raised the ticket on us when they got the
feature available.
>> Okay, good.
>> You know, true first class storage support, you know, built on top
of OneLake is also coming. Not in the so version that launched,
but in probably 137.
>> Okay.
>> Nearly made it. So that'll allow you to actually have this first
class kind of, you know, you know, file interface.
So if you want to go through there and allow people to
upload custom files, all those things.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> It has the nice Rafin abstraction on those things and then so
it's really easy to describe these things.
And the SDK is all nice.
>> Yep.
>> Then it's in onelake and you can do what you want with
it in OneLake. Just like data is just a database and you
can do what you want with the database.
And this is by design a lot of these things that we're
doing. Like we want you to have, you know, be able to
like talk to your functions, talk to your underlying database, talk to
your storage directly. Because if for some reason you're ever tired of,
you know, the limitations that BAZ is, you know, by design are
giving. Because we want you to kind of have on Rails experience,
you can always just go around us and talk to other learning
things yourselves and come up with your own REST API and all
that. We want you to be free to solve your problem.
>> Yes, please. I wish. So Chris, you missed the mark for me
a little bit. I needed you to build this about one and
a half years earlier. The only reason, because I needed it because
I built my website on GitHub pages and having your public facing
blog site would be awesome to land it right inside fabric.
And then I could get like, you want to upload something, I
want to have extra stuff or content downloadable for my site.
All of that can just live directly inside fabric and I don't
have to leave fabric for anything.
I mean this is, I don't think people understand how important all
of these Features are here and I think it's going to take
a bit, a couple time, a little bit of time, some months
for the community to get up to speed on what's going on,
why this is important. And I'm already seeing incredible things being built.
NJ park is one of the communities from mpps and he's built
every other day he's building some other frickin 3D Lego thing that
he's building and like what is this guy doing?
He's got bodies with human anatomy and organs.
He's like, I built a Ray Fin app and it's just amazing.
I'm like, this guy is on another level.
I absolutely love it. I think it's so cool.
With that being said, I know you've got some demo pieces.
Let's see what you've got cooking here.
And you're going to show us something interesting that we haven't really
experienced before when building with apps.
So let me just jump over here to the screen.
Let me minimize ourselves here. Okay, bringing up your desktop.
You're up. Your screen is there.
I can see an amazing teamwork app.
I guess it's on the right hand side there.
What's going on here?
>> Yeah, so some of the other, a little bit below the headline
announcements that we had is that we completely redid how our local
dev experience works. So if you ever kind of grabbed the project
locally and you looked at it, we had these instructions to run
NPM run device and that orchestrated a rafin up command and a
vite command and it was strung together within your own application space
and
it was fine. But one of the big issues that would happen
there is that if you were trying to load the local dev
experience inside of a embedded WebKit browser, which is what your copilots
and your VS codes, your non true browsers are doing.
Most corporate auth doesn't like random WebKit browsers, it turns out, so
your login would get hung up, pop ups wouldn't happen.
There was a whole lot of kind of hassle.
And then of course a lot of these things also don't keep
a local memory around for good reason.
You don't want all your random local hosts kind of like sharing
random local memory. But that also means that you do a refresh
and you get logged out and you got to log back in
again. And that means that the agent's trying to do things automated
for you, was constantly prompting you to go and hit the login
button and follow the prompts.
We did a bunch of investments into
the copilot plugin that we've got on awesome Copilot.
So you can find that inside of your GitHub Copilot app.
We've also got plugins for all the other major coding harnesses out
there and available as well. This now uses this universal template kind
of by default that comes with a lot of extra context and
skills about how all these things work.
And it's designed to know, oh, I'm running an agentic harness and
here's how I should behave then it uses a new command on
our cli. If you go and run your Rafen H, you'll go
through there and see this. If they're 1.3.6 version, we now have
Rafen dev for the really cool people who are playing around with
our feature flags and stuff. We used to have dev only for
this local docker based development which is cool for its own purposes
but broadly overkill for a lot of the people who are using
fabric and a lot of our users that we have today.
We wanted a lighter weight local dev experience.
What this does is it spins up a vite plugin still.
It spins up a proxy server within that vite plugin and it
will spin up functions code running locally as well.
So you can attach debuggers, etc.
To that one as well and rapidly.
Your agent can write code, you can write code and see those
changes immediately.
Then when you are running in this model, we actually will use
your RAF and CLI's auth context to automatically log you in if
you want to be able to test that locally.
But the default setting is that it's going to just log you
in automatically using your RAF and CLI context.
>> Sick again, the amount of work that you've done to reduce friction
for us developers and talking with these things.
Um, we were literally just before this, two hours before this, a
customer said hey, what's up with this Ray Fin thing?
I'm like let's build one. So we spent two hours like ripping
through the code and like let's fire up your agent here and
it's like fixing things and ripping stuff out.
We got menus and like within 30, 45 minutes we had a
full blown. They have an input system that they need to get
done. We, we stubbed out at least a piece of a POC
within 30 minutes and we're ready to go.
And already here you're showing me that there's already a full app
here you've got running that's on the right hand side.
So this is all copilot is what we're looking at here, right?
>> Yes, exactly. So this is the GitHub Copilot desktop app.
Super nice experience for your kind of more vibe coding kind of
development flows. Yes, obviously you can still see your files and all
those things in here. It's got a really nice experience for anyone
who hasn't tried it yet with just opening up in VS code
and it can actually. Oh, nice agent sessions.
Between VS code in here and your cli you can pick which
UX works best for you at the moment.
>> I like this.
>> It's running the actual local dev tools and stuff like that locally
here though I think this is not the session it's using right
now. It must have started a different background session.
Then
you've got the ability to host these canvases
browser and then you can do these custom canvases which I've actually
got a couple of these that we're not going to jump into
right now. But that allows you to actually create a custom little
local web app sort of like GitHub pages but with some of
the back end running locally to your project or generally useful across
projects if you want to build something.
We've got some prototypes.
>> Wow.
>> Ray Fin Canvas we can officially support which would have all your
different deployments that we're aware of and their status of things and
what branches they're on. So we'd really like to improve that visual
aspect of seeing where everything is at and what stage things are
on. But that's.
>> This is incredible. So one I, I have felt for a while
now Microsoft in general is, has been behind in like the agentic
development and like what we're trying to build and like this feels
like we've just pulled forward really fast and we're like right there
like we're thinking about ways like the creator agent.
I keep calling it the creator agent but I know this is
probably not the right term but it's, it's.
We want agents to help us build things.
Build things that run on commodity hardware, build things that run apps
that run in a repeatably deterministic way.
This is my app. It runs every single time, authors the same.
It's not this weird fuzzy thing that I'm trying to chat to
and get a consistent answer out of it.
This gives me the same report page view visuals every single time.
This is so good.
>> And I will say like the universal template.
One of the things that I'm really happy about that because I
know that a lot of people are going to be using Rafen,
you know for things Et cetera, as much as possible.
We don't want creating a whole bunch of debt that needs to
get cleaned up. A lot of what's in that template is actually
skills around what good web development patterns look like.
The hope there is that even if not all of our users
are considering themselves professional web developers, we've left them in a really
good place with the agent following really good patterns for how to
structure your react projects. What are how to maintain and check accessibility.
If I were to scan through here, you'd see it doing accessibility
checks as I was building up the application, making sure that the
colors that it chose weren't awful for that purposes.
There's a lot of things that agents really help make possible that
would otherwise just end up being we keep you two on the
Rails. This is a really nice balance of we're keeping you on
the Rails from a service perspective, but from a presentation layer we
can really let you kind of go go free, you know, as
free as you want to go.
One of the things I want to also point out here, if
you're using this, I love this, like just click and select things.
So rather than like what component I'm talking to like oh yeah,
label and the filter form, I can just.
It'll actually reference this and I can tell it to go and
like change something about it.
>> So this is a direct feature.
So there was one feature that I liked a lot which this
is a. Something I saw with some early agentic coding.
It was called Agentation, which was like the.
It had like a little icon and you could like click into
it and it would then highlight all the divs around the page.
And this also, I believe it's also a function of VS code.
Absolutely love it. And it's. It's sending enough information like where that
position is, what it's labeled as, how it gets to the page
just enough so the agent knows what to fix.
So it's not digging through and searching for like a hundred of
things in the code. You're very like.
You can be very pointed around the very specific thing that you're
looking for.
>> Exactly.
>> Amazing.
>> Then I think one other thing that we announced functions obviously but
one of the things that can get missed there is that one
of those connectors that supported via the functions piece actually to Azure
DevOps there's some constraints around how authentication works there going to get
loosened over time as we kind of figure out the right ways
of making sure that everything kind of stays completely on the right
Rails. But we were able to release it with Enough constraints to
make sure that we weren't going to be totally surprised.
And so what I actually have here is I've got a little
hide filters, things you don't see our real actual backlog.
>> One of them on there is like, build more stuff for Mike
because he needs help with all these Rafin things.
>> There's a decent number of your feature requests in this pile here.
>> All right.
>> But the, you know, we have, you know, you know, just like
every team does probably, like, we've got regular scrums, we kind of
go through status on things, we're tracking things that are like GA
required, we triage things that don't have labels and all that kind
of stuff. And so, sure, we've kind of built a bunch of,
you know, queries and ADO and we've tried to optimize this within
the Azure DevOps experience. And honestly, it's, you know, it's pretty good.
But what's awesome about, you know, this kind of new world that
we're in and what Rafen really enables is that I can build
stuff which is like optimized for how our team wants to work.
Like, what are the. This is it.
I need to go like, you know, I can't see a random
query and then like also see a Gantt chart in the same
view right now in ado, but I can go there and
>> just tell co here, build it.
>> We'll go through there and pull in beta and build it all
for me.
>> Yeah, 100%. And this is the kind of stuff like this is.
You don't get a colored. Go get a gradient colored bar inside
Power Bi desktop. Like you maybe can do it.
You might be writing a whole bunch of HTML.
You're still probably going to invoke some sort of agent to help
you get some cool stuff like this.
But like, I see your bars here.
Again, I'm going to be nitpicky here, right?
You've got bars with square ends on the left, rounded edges on
the top. I mean, dude,
the limit is what's inside your head now and how to get
stuff out of here. One. This is polished.
Looks really good. Love the color schema that you're picking and you're
building here. You know this Gantt chart with like dots, targets, things
like track on track. This is finessed.
>> I can click on this and it brings me to the work
item.
>> Yes.
>> Think of the DAX expressions here, right?
>> Oh, yeah, this would be horrendous.
I would never. Yes, but, but you're building.
So this is bringing the App data.
So much closer directly to what you're building in the data data
or the semantic world data. And the fact that you're able to
bolt this on, I can't. So my team has working, has been
working in DevOps. We love working in GitHub for our internal projects.
Man, I don't like DevOps anymore.
The fact that I get a DevOps at least a DevOps MCP
server, like, I'm happy now. The fact that you gave me like
way better. I can like rip out tasks, I can have stuff
made a lot faster. So I'm using a whole bunch more MCP
stuff with my agents inside, inside DevOps.
So I'm not negative against it, but I'm just saying, like any
tools that we're able to build that has tighter integration to like
agents and talking and doing things, I fully imagine here.
I mean, you're talking about grooming things down here.
There's no reason why you can't hook up a foundry to the
back end of this and say, hey, by the way, if a
customer comes in here or a business user wants to come in
and say, I want to ask questions about this, or I wanted
to add new tickets items directly here.
You could tell that information to Foundry, Foundry can come back and
you can directly start moving things right back to DevOps.
This is the custom of the process.
This is so powerful.
>> Yeah. I certainly think that getting official support for
agents as a primitive to Rafin is the thing that we are
trying to make happen as quickly as we can.
Because for the exact scenario that you were just talking about,
I've got this lovely thing here and I've built some nice.
Let me switch it to a me view here.
I've got this feature here and if I want to move it
to execution, we've got this rule here that says that for execution,
I've got to fill in all these fields.
But it would be awesome if I could just have a quick
voice to text or something like that.
>> Target is this. Yeah.
>> And tell it to like, guess like the right answer to these
things based of what I've been doing.
And you know, the agents running inside of the app here, you
know, quickly enter these things for me and move it on.
Because, you know, obviously in Scrum, what we care about is like
moving through as quickly as we can and, you know, trying to
maximize the time that we're saving for conversations and not spending much
of time, you know, talking about which fields need to be filled
incorrectly.
>> That's waste of our time. Agents are way Smarter to figure this
and it. You could also use things like grill me.
Right? This would be another great one of these opportunities.
Like hey, I want to get.
I have a new issue. Here's when it's due.
And this also would allow us to be able to be in
like we are best spent being the human part of things.
Right. We need to talk to others, we need to relate to
them. We need to have to have the conversation More and more
I'm finding I need to. I need transcripts, I need summaries.
All of those need to turn into details work that we're going
to track. I don't need to be involved in all that.
Copilot does a great job summarizing my meeting notes.
Shove it in here. Just make, hey look, go through my meeting,
add all the stuff that I care about or here's my meeting
notes. Boom, make tickets for me.
That's the kind of stuff. This is huge.
>> We do actually have a custom agent for our team which does
all those things for us.
>> Oh nice.
>> That's all
custom that we've built but our goal is to be able to
run everything like that on an actual fabric hosted Rafen app.
>> That's amazing.
>> One of the things we can like you said with functions, it's
all just code. Here's the actual code here.
>> Yeah, let's see.
>> This is that with 1.3.6 the new default template that we've got
moves to this now multi package thing.
So if you are trying to do code reuse and stuff like
that, it's a lot easier to do that now than it was
before. So it's much more modern JavaScript project format here my functions
package and inside of here I've got my function app.
Then you can see here that there's a specific library here that
we've got for handling all the ado logic that the agent wrote.
I don't have all my logic in a single file like we
do for Python functions. You can break it up how you want
to. Then there is some generated code here for the secrets typing
pieces and then there is some generated code here for the the
public API surface area. I'm hoping to actually get at least this
part not needing to be generated every single time that you start
again. Secrets is always going to need to be generated because it's
remote. Your secrets are defined by what's there on the target you're
pointing at. That will generate it occasionally.
>> Awesome.
>> It's back end code. You can do whatever you want inside of
here you can talk to whatever random third party APIs.
We don't have a plugin yet for talking to GitHub for example.
And I was actually working through how can I go through there
and pull the GitHub issues that we've got also into this.
>> Oh yeah, because there's a whole public issues that's on top of
things and you want to have them.
Yeah, that makes total sense here.
Merge all that data back into your ado.
>> And yeah, I was kind of working in a different branch on
basically what kind of function would I add for those things.
I needed to go through there and Register a new GitHub app
that would have the right permissions and all that kind of stuff.
It's all possible. Some really interesting things have also happened.
You know Jacob Knightley, right?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, awesome guy, very awesome. He actually figured out that he could
create a custom Enter app and use a Rafin app as like
thing you log into. So like right now you don't have to
create a custom Enter app for your thing, but you could and
then pass that token down into your function and have your function
just call arbitrary things that your entrapp is scoped to.
So obviously that's not easy. So like I'm not going to call
that done. We're not going to develop any more features for racing.
Truly what you were saying, there is truth to what you said
of like now you can kind of do anything like as long
as you're willing to maybe do a little bit of extra work
on getting your own permissions and storing your own secrets, et cetera.
For some of the things that we don't have out of the
box support for connecting to today, but you really are open to
doing almost anything. Talking to foundries is entirely possible assuming that you
have the custom Entra app to have permission to go talk to
your foundry models, et cetera. So
if you're really excited about doing this, the sky's the limit.
And then our hope here is that we'll keep rapidly adding new
connectors and keep on adding some of these new capabilities so that
it just works out of the box.
Our goal is that Ray Fin up just works and that you're
not having to go through there and run around and figure out
a whole bunch of configuration
when you have to go and talk to your security team eventually.
If you want to have a business critical application, we want as
much as possible for Rafin to be self describing and your security
team to have confidence that the sandbox that your tenant admin settings
are enforcing the right things you can streamline a lot of those
review processes as well.
>> I think there's a part of this where I'm looking at this
going. There's this idea of the custom harness, the custom process, the
custom app. More and more organizations are finding like this, right.
I can build very comprehensive, very useful tools.
I don't need to go buy a bunch of software that's doing
all this stuff for me. I now need a great surface area
of APIs and bots that are smart that can figure out how
to weed those APIs together. And then we build the front end
again, going back to the graph, whatever we want to do, we
can build anything now. We can have anything as we can dream
it. We can now start crafting the process around the app so
we have the process that's our ip.
And as a company, this allows us to craft an experience around
it that makes it easier to use.
Amazing.
>> I think what's, you know, what's really cool here is that, like,
when you're trying to talk about like, do I buy software?
Do I build software? You know, before you would like, you know,
try to guess how much it was going to cost you to
build it, and then guess how much it was going to, you
know, take to maintain it. And then, you know, try to compare
that against procuring something and have a whole kind of procurement process
depending on what your company's policies are.
>> Sure.
>> And with agents, I think that there's definitely a, you know, building
something is now relatively cheap now, building it for real, supporting it,
all those kinds of things are still valid concerns.
You know, it goes beyond just software.
Like, sometimes you need to have specific legal and compliance expertise on
things that, you know, when you're working with vendors who specialize in
those things, it's still just economically better to work with them.
But one of the issues that I sometimes have when I have
to work with a different piece of software which is kind of
optimized around
how they manage the data and stuff like that.
They're not necessarily selling how good their visuals or experiences are.
They're selling the true business problem they're trying to solve, which is
often about their data or how they're processing data, et cetera.
And so Rafin and this kind of model of like, well, let
me build my own front end on top of this
SaaS layer. It's super powerful because I can bring in all those
sasses together. Like I said, I was trying to bring GitHub into
this.
We have a semantic model inside of fabric for all of our
deployment pipelines and where the trains are and stuff.
And, and so like I want to be able to like see
this full nature of like these are the items, these are the
trains they're targeting. This is when that train is leaving.
Here's all the things that are in this train and like that
all in a single pane of glass.
And you know, Rafen makes that super easy to do thanks to
agents making that really easy to build once the data is made
available in a secure way. And like that, that's what Rafen's trying.
Rayfin and Fabric apps is trying to solve is like make the
data available in a secure way.
That is for the agent to then, you know, build whatever you
want to dream up, add your fancy particle visuals to your site.
>> All.
>> All the silly things you want to go and do.
Yeah. Gosh. I think you've talked with Ben.
Like Ben has some of the, the funnest apps where he's just
always adding, yes, surprising.
>> You got to look something crazy things all the time.
This is. And this is, this is exciting where we're in such
a neat world right now. So I, I do want to be
mindful of your time, Chris. You're a very busy person.
You, I saw your backlog. There's so many things for you to
knock out done. I don't want to delay you from getting great
new features out the door, but I do want to say a
heartfelt thank you for. This was the very last minute we were
talking Tuesday. I said with this work, we like, yeah, let's do
something calendar. So I'm extremely excited about Rayfin.
Rayfin is going to be a very critical tool in your tool
stack. When you're talking about fabric and Power bi.
This does not directly replace only Power BI reports.
I think there's still a place and time for those things as
well. But this is going to be a huge advantage for organizations.
And the one friction that I think you're speaking to here is
anymore as a, as a business owner, as a person who consults
with companies, I really don't. I get so impatient with other companies
and how hard it is to get their data out of the
systems. And so there's this idea of like, I've already built the
software. Like I'm already going to use GitHub, I'm going to use
DevOps. Like it's there. That's where the data works.
That's where everyone is understanding. I get it.
There's a, there's a, a critical mass that I'm not going to
move. But if I'm a smaller business, if I'm a newer company,
if I'm actually evaluating net new software that I'm thinking about creating,
I'm being really, I'm watching Ray Fin very closely because I really
do believe that the advantage of not only being able to customize
the app to your work process, you get a major benefit by.
It's just in fabric. You got all the tables, there's no data,
extra access. It all lives in fabric.
And I think this factor alone is enough to push every business.
They must go look at fabric apps specifically for this data is
in the same place. Everyone can touch it.
That's huge.
>> I think, I think that, you know, if you look through like
the history of the cloud and how that, you know, how the
business has kind of evolved and grown in the space, you had
this kind of element, you know, credit to Salesforce where they were
disruptive by just, you know, kind of having one of those first
big enterprise sasses. And you were seeing organizations, you know, shadow it
adopt this stuff because it was so much more productive and they
enabled that pattern really easily. Yeah, definitely remember having a Salesforce here
at Microsoft that's already paid with their amex until they got caught
for it.
They couldn't figure out how to like run Dynamics at the time
and then. Right, exactly is great now.
But you know, there was disruptive moment that was, that was happening.
And I do think that this ability to kind of like, you
know, build whatever you want to with custom data if you want,
bring in, you know, some of your existing data if you need
to and that every combination therein, like, you know, do I want
to combine my analytics visuals with my transactional data, all that kind
of stuff. Like you are really more free to do that by
with less effort and you know, less like safety concerns.
I mean again, you should still have processes for anything super critical
but like there should be a lot more streamlined with, with the
kind of constraints that we've got is, is the hope.
And so like I, I do wonder whether this is like, you
know, the start of a new kind of shadow IT era where
like, oh, you make it really hard.
>> Don't say that bad word.
>> And you know, the CRM or, you know.
Yeah, these different kinds of things.
Well, people build their own, you know, versions of those software that
you were like, that's the thing.
Procurement process is the number one thing that blocks most people from
actually being able to go and get the software that they need.
And a lot of companies still, Microsoft is Not necessarily an exception
in all cases. Right. And if I've got the choice of, like,
going through this long procurement process and having to deal with all
these extra hassles and all that, versus just build weekend what I
need in weekends.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, that is interesting. You know, I think it's disruptive and
I think that it definitely kind of will make, you know, assuming
that, that we. We do see people doing more of that, you're
going to have to see businesses respond by making their APIs more
available to be accessed in this way.
Yes. To think of themselves not so much as a, hey, we
own your experience and your life for this particular part of the
world, but hey, we're enabling you to solve a problem alongside everything
else. You know, I think very possible that you kind of, you
know, start to see those big major shifts.
We're probably already seeing some of those big, major shifts.
>> I'm going to, I'm going to give you a really, a tangible
example audience here. I use QuickBooks for my business to send out
invoices and manage things. They don't have an MCP server built into
their service. Shocker. Right?
>> We're QuickBooks.
>> You don't. We don't bend to your will.
You bend to our will. Right.
And so I'm actually actively looking at like, well, that.
I mean, I pay a lot of money to you guys and
yet you don't give me what I need to do to like,
write my statements of work. And I should be able to talk
to an agent and say, hey, bot, now that we get these
dot things from which I think the bot dot things that are
out there, it's hilarious. They're just.
These guys are just poking at each other at this point.
But, but that being said, I want to just go talk to
my agent and be like, hey, look, I've got this new customer.
Draft up my, my statement of work.
Go make the, the. The estimate.
This is what I want in it.
Like, these are the kind of things that we're need to be
building. Tommy on the podcast for explicit measures.
He's got an entire sales team built out as bots, getting and
looking for leads and finding things and scraping and dude, I'm telling
you, we are in a such a exciting time to be in
this creation space. So it's not going to take our jobs.
It's definitely not.
>> It's way less. Like, can you.
It's way more. Should you. These days.
>> Yes, exactly. Right. So with that being said, I really want to
thank you for your time. This has been wonderful.
We could chit chat and talk about how exciting this is over
and over again. Stay tuned if you like Chris's comments, if you
like the demo he showed here.
If you like seeing some of the things behind Rafen, let us
know in the comments. What did you like?
What do you want to see more of?
I will also give some big kudos here.
Chris, you have been busy. I now go to the Rafen templates
and there used to be like three or four of them.
I see like 10 of them.
You've been busy creating a lot of
>> extra templates here to leave and a bunch of them piled up.
I burned through those when I got back.
>> Yeah.
>> Also call out the the Rafin GitHub issues you know, are more
and more love and I expect there to be a big surprise
there very, very soon for what's available on that repo beyond what's
currently there.
>> All right, stay tuned.
>> Definitely. If you have feature requests and stuff like that listening stop
by the Microsoft Rafin repo in addition to the awesome Rafin which
has got all the great templates.
But that Rafin repo is a great place to file your feature
requests, ask questions and
the it was a little bit cold because I think I was
on there wasn't as much attention on that as there should have
been. But I'm back baby. So
we're ready to go.
>> I love it. I love it.
So both links to both awesome Rafin is in the chat window
as well and I've also put in here also the ray fin
directly and I'll make sure I add those to the show notes
under the description as well so you get that well.
So make sure you give us a thumbs up.
If you like this kind of content, let us know.
It's easy, it's free. You can already hit the thumbs up that
helps other people hear and find this as well.
Chris, thank you so much. And with everyone else here, I'm going
to leave you with an AI song as we wrap for this
session. Thank you all so much.
I'll see you in the future.
Thanks Chris.
>> Thanks.
>> Who you are shows up and every field you choose
and the colors that you favor and the truth you use.
Power Be I eye isn't just a place to click.
It's a mirror of the person behind the tree.
Your identity, your identity.
Your identity. Not just what you build.
It's who you mean to be.
Your identity.
Some of us are builders chasing perfect form.
Some of us storytellers keeping numbers warm.
Some of us are guardians of the single soul all of us
are feeling? Fingerprint inside the course?
Your identity? Your identity? Predicting the world to see?
Your identity? Your identity? Just what you build Is who you mean
to be?
In your identity?
So does who you are?
Stay close to the reason that you started this identity Is louder
than the featureless? Don't trade your voice on someone else's char?
Don't hide your crap behind a borrowed heart?
Boys feel human when the driver rises?
Because somebody honest put their soul inside?
Standing in the glow of a four on the floor?
Night?
>> I remember why?
>> Built when the patch feel right?
Power be holds a piece of me?
And a piece of my? My identity?
Your identity?
You.
Better.
Sam.